Vadim Akhmetov

Moscow

Tel: +7 926 666 81 02

golden312va@gmail.com



Profile

Data Scientist with strong math background and two year of experience using predictive modeling, data processing, and data mining algorithms to solve challenging business problems. Involved in Python open source community and passionate about deep learning.

Experience

Data Scientist, Rosbank, Moscow - November 2020 - current

I was engaged in increasing the quality of the credit bank scoring model, photo scoring for the prob default and OCR (recognition of text information from documents) on the Unified State Register of Legal Entities / property rights documents.

Improving the credit default scoring based on transactional data. External anti-fraud.

Data Scientist, DemandTec, Moscow — November 2020 - May 2021

I was engaged in the support and expansion of the optimization engine functionality (on Pytorch).

The engine was used to optimize the elasticity function in order to predict the best price, taking into account business rules.

Teacher / project manager, Educational Center «Sirius», Sochi — April 2021

With the children, we implemented a project to monitor compliance with safety regulations (part of it). The presence of a helmet on a person, using PoseEstimation and OpenCV for color filtering in specific area.

Data Scientist, Sberbank, Moscow — November 2019 - November 2020

I was responsible for data markup aggregation, employee outflow models, forecasting the number of new employees in different departments, Optical Character Recognition models (segmentation + text detection + text recognition), face defects detection.

Computer Vision Engineer, «Algomost» Ltd., Moscow — April 2020 - July 2020 I was involved in development of classical and neural video analysis algorithms in order to automize manufacturing process.

Teacher / project manager, Educational Center «Sirius», Sochi — February 2020

Taught children Python programming for them to be able to develop IoT project. IoT project development included working with Backend, Frontend, SQLAlchemy, Flask, Arduino programming with Python. As a result of my teaching process my students have developed a web service, that allowed to monitor signals arriving from pipes' sensors, and to process them.

Teacher / project manager, Educational Center «Sirius», Sochi — December 2019

Taught children Python programming and Computer Vision for their further developing auto-cucumbercollector. With the help of neural network YOLOv3 recognized cucumbers from the pictures and basing on bounding boxes navigated CNC machine to collect them.

Education RUDN University, Moscow — PhD, current

RUDN University, Moscow — Master, 2020 RUDN University, Moscow — Bachelor, 2018

Skils Machine Learning, Deep Learning, SQL, Python, OpenCV, Computer Vision, NLP,

Information Retrieval, Time Series Analysis, Docker.